# TESSA NEWMAN-HEGGIE

Marquette, MI · 651-503-6806

 $tnewmanheggie@gmail.com \cdot github.com/tnewmanheggie \cdot www.tnewmanheggie.com$ 

Full-stack software engineer specializing in Ruby on Rails and React Native. I consider myself languageagnostic and love learning new programming languages. I have experience with every part of the software development process, from scoping to deployment.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT**

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SHIFT INTERACTIVE**

Engineered an employee health and wellness platform and mobile app backend with over 1 million users. Collaborated with a team to scope, build and deliver features with weekly deployments.

## **DECEMBER 2020 – OCTOBER 2021**

# JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SHIFT INTERACTIVE

Led the development of a React Native Mobile app, leveraging a Ruby on Rails backend and integrations of several APIs. Shipped iOS and Android apps to app stores on a tight deadline.

#### **SUMMER 2020**

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN, SHIFT INTERACTIVE**

Built full-stack RoR applications with a team while employing Agile. Performed in the top 50% of company engineers based on productivity measures.

#### **SUMMER 2019**

# NLP RESEARCH INTERN, CS LABORATORY AT UNIVERSITÉ PARIS SUD

Built NLP Lifelong Learning AI system in Python used to train medical school students all over the world. Communicated primarily in French and led the development of the AI's English phrase catalog.

# **EDUCATION**

# **B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE AND LINGUISTICS** CARLETON COLLEGE

GPA: 3.9, Dean's List (2018-2019, 2017-2018), Minor in French

## SKILLS

- Languages: Ruby on Rails, Python, React Native, JavaScript, Scheme, C, SQL, CSS, HTML
- Frameworks/Tools: Heroku, PostgreSQL, GitHub, CircleCl

# **ACTIVITIES**

# **PRESIDENT, SUSTAINABILITY COMMITTEE**

Coordinated company-wide initiatives to engage and educate coworkers about sustainable issues and current events related to the worldwide climate crisis. Presented weekly updates and tips at company-wide meetings.